生存还是毁灭
To be, or not to be,
这是个问题
that is the question.
默默忍受命运
Whether it is nobler --
默默忍受命运...
Whether it -- Whether it's -- What?
默然忍受命运...
Whether 'tis -- Whether 'tis -- 'tis -- 'tis.
体会台词  产生共鸣
Connect to the words. Connect to me.
Connect the words to me.
生存还是毁灭
To be, or not to be,
这是个问题
that is the question.
默然忍受命运...
Whether 'tis nobler in the mind to suffer --
谁啊
Hello?
有人吗
Who's there?
太棒了
Yes!
我好久没见过你这么激动
Wow, I haven't seen you this excited since,
上次还是...今天早上
uh, well, earlier this morning, so...
知道这是什么吗  贝克特
You know what this is, Beckett?
不  但我知道
Uh, no, but I know that
是一个信使刚送到的
a very secure messenger just brought it in.
天呐
Oh, my.
简直美极了
It's absolutely beautiful.
是什么
What is it?
YOLO卡
The YOLO card.
是"哥们  我刚把老妈的车开进河里
Like, "Dude, I just drove my mom's car into the river --
#人生只有一次"吗
#YOLO"?
不不不  这
No, no, no, this --
这件艺术品
This work of art
将永远把YOLO从网络牢笼中释放出来
will forever release YOLO from Internet jail.
每张卡都是由一群国际艺术家
You see, each card was painstakingly handcrafted
费心手工制造的
by an international team of artisans.
看到卡片内嵌的
Note the flecks of actual black diamond
黑钻石碎片了吧
embedded in the card.
还有先进的无线电频率身份芯片
The state-of-the-art radio frequency I.D. chip.
最棒的是
The -- The best part --
全世界只有一万人
Only 10,000 people in the world
被选中持有YOLO卡
were chosen to have a YOLO card,
我就是其中之一
and I'm one of them.
卡塞尔  这就是张信用卡
Castle, it's just a credit card.
只是张信用卡
Just a credit card?
恐怕不是  好女人
I think not, my good woman.
这是张YOLO卡  即"人生只有一次"
This is a YOLO, as in, "You only live once."
这是一种生活方式
It is a way of life.
-是烦人的方式还差不多  -是吗
- No, it's a way to be obnoxious. - Oh, is it?
每天我花钱抓住自己当下的生活时
You see, for every dollar I spend seizing my own day,
YOLO会花等量的钱帮助不幸的他人
YOLO matches it to help someone less fortunate
去抓住他们的梦想
seize their dreams.
这么一说不那么烦人了
Oh, okay. Well, that's a little less obnoxious.
我也是觉得
That's what I thought.
所以你想试用一下吗
So, you want to try it out, take it for a spin?
或许你今晚用得上
Might help you with tonight.
今晚干什么
What's tonight?
拜托  你不是忘了吧
Come on. Don't tell me you forgot.
我们的每周约会之夜  我们的新传统啊
Our weekly date night. It's new. It's our thing.
该你安排了  记得吗
It's -- It's your turn to arrange it, remember?
记得
Yeah.
我当然记得
Of cour-- Of course I remember.
我不需要YOLO卡帮我安排
I don't need a YOLO card to help me out with that.
我已经都安排好了
I've already got it planned.
是吗
Oh, do you?
告诉我  你打算如何超越
So, tell me, how are you gonna top
我之前安排的美国革命之夜
my American Revolution evening I arranged
马车拉去百老汇看《汉密尔顿》
with the carriage ride to see "Hamilton" on Broadway,
在服务员扮成开国元勋的餐厅吃饭
the dinner served by waiters dressed as Founding Fathers?
是啊  那是很有趣
Yes, that was fun.
直到本·富兰克林开始泡我
Except for when Ben Franklin started hitting on me.
那没什么
That's nothing.
乔治·华盛顿还把电话塞给了我
George Washington slipped me his digits.
什么
What?!
我们今晚做什么
So, what are we doing tonight?
是个惊喜  卡塞尔
Uh, well, it's a surprise, Castle.
我喜欢惊喜
Oh, I love surprises.
至少告诉我该穿什么
At least tell me what to wear.
隆重程度从1到10
On a wardrobe scale of 1 to 10 --
10是007  1是《谋杀绿脚趾》的督爷
10 being James Bond, 1 being "Big Lebowski" --
说个数吧
give me a number.
现在  5  犯罪现场休闲装
For now? 5 -- crime-scene casual.
嗯
Uh, yeah.
很好  谢谢
That's great. Thanks.
那是赞恩·卡侬吗
Is that Zane Cannon?
是的  《末日逃亡》系列影片的主角
Yep, star of the "Apocalypse Runner" movie franchise.
我喜欢那个系列
I love those movies.
我也喜欢  不过  无意对死者不敬
Yeah, me too, even though -- no disrespect to the dead --
这人的演技也保不了命[演技烂]
this guy couldn't act to save his life.
-可不是  看他啊  -是啊
- Quite literally, by the looks of things. - Yeah.
赞恩今早在独自彩排《哈姆雷特》吗
Was Zane rehearsing "Hamlet" alone this morning?
其实  是昨晚
Actually, it was last night.
法医认为死亡时间
The M.E. places the time of death
是昨晚8点到11点
between 8:00 and 11:00 p.m.
羽毛笔
A quill pen.
选这么奇怪的凶器  除非
Odd choice for a murder weapon, unless, of course,
凶手是威廉·莎士比亚的鬼魂
the murderer was the ghost of William Shakespeare
看不惯赞恩糟蹋他的剧本而杀了他
killing Zane for butchering his words.
据百老汇的传闻
It's all the talk on Broadway
赞恩根本不该
that Zane had no business
出演莎翁最负盛名的角色
performing the Bard's most famous role.
那为什么选他演
Why cast him, then?
因为电影明星好卖票
Because movie stars sell tickets.
问我妈就知道了
Just ask my mother.
她一直在夸夸其谈
She can't stop talking about
百老汇的好莱坞化问题
the Hollywood-ization of Broadway.
等等
Hold on.
你干什么呢
Hey, what are you doing?
-给我  -我就是
- Give me that. - I was just --
想得美
Nice try.
我已经上传至云端了
I already uploaded it to the cloud.
警官  把这混蛋送出去
Hey, Officer, escort this dirtbag out of here
没收他的外套
and confiscate that jacket.
那是我的电话
That -- That -- That's my phone.
你无权拿走我的电话
You -- You legally can't have that phone.
把我的电话给我
Hey, give me my phone!
瞧  被害人的名声
See that? Our victim's fame
已经让此事变成媒体的闹剧
is already turning this into a media circus.
各位  容我向你们介绍
Hey, fellas, may I introduce to you
艾琳·切尔洛夫
Erin Cherloff?
她是本剧的导演  真正的艺术家
She is the play's director and a true artist.
你导演的《安提戈涅》真是发人深省
Your production of "Antigone" was a revelation.
谢谢
Oh, well, thank you.
真不敢相信会发生这种事
I-I can't believe this is happening.
赞恩和我时隔这么多年终于有机会
Zane and I finally get a chance to work together
一起合作了  就发生这种事
after all these years, and this happens.
-你俩是朋友吗  -对  戏剧学院认识的
- The two of you were friends? - Yeah, since theater school.
赞恩退学去好莱坞闯荡了
Zane dropped out to go to Hollywood,
但我们一直关系很好
but we stayed close.
你知道他昨晚为什么会
Do you know what he was doing here
一个人来剧院吗
in the theater by himself last night?
他很害怕  怕《哈姆雷特》
He was terrified... of "Hamlet."
他真心想通过这个角色表现自己的演技
He really wanted to show his acting chops in this role.
有时候他会下班后来加班练习
Sometimes he would come here after hours to work more.
就你所知  赞恩跟谁有矛盾吗
Was Zane having problems with anyone you know of?
他有跟女主角上床的习惯
It's no secret he had a reputation
这已不是秘密
for sleeping with his leading ladies.
你是说赞恩在跟饰演
Are you saying Zane was sleeping with
奥菲莉亚的女演员上床吗
the actress playing Ophelia?
纳奥米·福克斯
Naomi Fox.
他们最近分手了  闹得很大
They had a messy breakup recently.
她一副《致命诱惑》不肯放手的样子
She sort of went all "Fatal Attraction."
她拿棒球棒砸了他的DB9
So she took a baseball bat to his DB9.
他为了保险申诉让我拍了照片
He had me take photos for his insurance.
-他有报警吗  -没有
- Did he report that to the police? - No.
我跟纳奥米合作过  她是疯
Look, I-I've worked with Naomi before, and she's crazy,
但是演员那种疯  不是杀人犯那种
but actor crazy, not murderer crazy.
但有个小问题
However, there is one teeny, tiny, little thing
你们该知道
you should know about.
纳奥米是个方法派演员
Naomi's a method actor,
就是说她并不扮演角色
meaning she doesn't play the characters.
而是要变成角色
She becomes them.
你知道我们要去哪找到她吗
Do you know where we can find her?
希望我刚刚不会太过
I just hope I wasn't too obvious back there.
我实在太喜欢艾琳·切尔洛夫了
I'm just such a big fan of Erin Cherloff.
-那个导演吗  -她太棒了
- Who, the director? - Yeah, she's amazing.
刚跟她说话时  我突然想到个
I'm -- Just speaking with her, I got this great idea
萨拉·格蕾丝幼儿园剧的好点子
for the play at Sarah Grace's preschool
我是志愿者
where I'm a parent volunteer at.
等等  幼儿园现在都演剧了
Wait, preschools have plays now?
我的幼儿园就是每天跟妈妈上班
My preschool was going to work with my mom every day.
我也是
Oh, same here.
我就在这样的走廊里长大
I grew up in hallways just like this.
在妈妈的换衣室里待着
Spending time in my mother's dressing room,
拿她的戏服  化妆品玩
experimenting with her costumes, her makeup.
得了
Oh, get over it.
总之  或许我们的方法派演员太入戏了
Anyway, maybe our method actress has gone a little too method.
在剧中  哈姆雷特将奥菲莉亚逼疯
In the play, Hamlet drives Ophelia mad.
如果生活模拟了艺术  而她彻底疯了
If this is life imitating art and she's gone full Ophelia,
我们得做好一切准备
we should be ready for anything.
福克斯女士
Ms. Fox?
纽约警局  我们需要问你几个问题
NYPD. We need to ask you a few questions.
福克斯女士
Ms. Fox.
我来
Um, may I?
奥菲莉亚
Ophelia?
是  大人
Aye, my lord?
这两位先生是警官
These fair gentlemen are constables
他们想就下作可怕的
and wish to speak with you in matters regarding
赞恩·卡侬谋杀案跟你谈谈
the murder most foul and unnatural of Zane Cannon.
太可怕了  让人不忍去想
'Tis too much to bear to think on it.
得了  美丽的奥菲莉亚
How now, fair Ophelia?
我们有问题  你必须解答
We have queries, and thou shall answer,
否则我们就将不得不请你...
or we shall force perforce be moved to make a star chamber --
行了
Stop.
我们绝不要玩这套
We are so not doing this.
纳奥米  我们知道你跟赞恩搞上了
Look, Naomi, we know that you were having a show-mance with Zane.
他甩了你  你就砸烂了他的车
He dumped you, and then you busted up his car.
大人  他的语气好奇怪
My lord, he speaks with a curious tongue.
车
Car?
等他以杀人嫌疑逮捕你时
It's what he's gonna put you in the back of
会送你坐上其后座的
when he arrests you for murder.
别再跟我玩刘皇叔这套  开始交待  否则
So stop the Daniel Day-Lewis routine and start talking, or...
听着  我砸赞恩的车时
Okay, look, I wasn't in my right mind
是一时冲动
when I smashed up Zane's car,
但我没杀他
but I didn't kill him.
你们得相信我
You have to believe me.
我昨晚跟几个
I was out late last night
其他卡司一起逛酒吧到很晚
bar-hopping with some of the cast.
你们可以去查证
You can check it out.
逛酒吧  你也不是完全入戏嘛
Bar-hopping? So you're not full method.
除非她喝的是蜂蜜酒  还用手吃东西
Unless she was drinking mead and eating with her fingers.
听着  我真心在乎赞恩
Look, I really cared for Zane,
但他好像出轨了
but he was acting like he was cheating on me,
晚上很晚跑去我那儿
showing up at my place at all hours of the night,
找各种烂借口
lame excuses.
所以我质问了他  他就爆发了
So I confronted him, and he blew up,
叫我再也不要问他都去哪
told me never to ask where he goes again.
-知道他出轨的对象可能是谁吗  -不
- Any idea who this other woman might be? - No.
但不管她是谁  她引出了他黑暗的一面
But whoever she was, she brought out his dark side.
我们为您带来关于好莱坞巨星
We have breaking news on the shocking death
赞恩·卡侬令人震惊之死的报道
of Hollywood megastar Zane Cannon,
他的尸体今早被发现于
whose body was found this morning onstage
非百老汇的公民剧院舞台上
at the off-Broadway Citizens Theater.
为什么新闻上有赞恩尸体的视频
So, why is there a video of Zane's body on the news?
一个跟踪狂/狗仔穿了件纽约警局的外套
A stalker-azzi snuck onto the crime scene
偷偷溜进了犯罪现场
wearing an NYPD windbreaker.
据在现场的消息源透露
A source at the scene reveals
负责调查这位明星之死的
that leading the investigation into the star's murder
正是盛名远扬的侦探小说家  理查德·卡塞尔
is none other than acclaimed mystery writer Richard Castle
并有纽约警局12分局的协助
with an assist from the NYPD's 12th Precinct.
总局一直叮嘱我要控制媒体报道
1PP has been on my ass about keeping media under control,
现在我丈夫还成了调查的脸面
and now my husband is the face of the investigation.
-并不都是坏消息  贝克特  -怎么说
- It's not all bad news, Beckett. - How?
我那张照片非常好看
That's a great photo of me.
有嫌疑人了吗
Do we have a suspect?
还没有  纳奥米的不在场证明核实了
Not yet. Naomi's alibi checked out.
但我们有关于
But we do have a lead
与赞恩约会的神秘女子的线索了
on this mystery woman that Zane was seeing.
他的财务情况查到了
His financials came in.
他昨天早上租了一辆豪车
They say that he rented a limo yesterday morning.
可以理解  纳奥米砸了他的DB9嘛
Which makes sense, since Naomi trashed his DB9.
-豪车去了哪  -还不知道
- And where was this limo going? - I don't know yet.
我还在等司机的回电
I'm still waiting for the driver to call me back,
但希望他知道那女子是谁
but hopefully he knows who this woman is.
我已经找到了她
I have already found her.
原来赞恩用假名在
It turns out that Zane was renting a suite
黑门酒店租了间房
at the Black Door Hotel under a fake name.
黑门啊  很上档次嘛
Ah, the Black Door. Yes, very fancy.
保密性非常好
Known for being discreet...
我是这么听说的
is what I've heard
听一些曾经单身
from other people who were once single
现在已婚的人说的
and now married.
他们的确是
Well, they certainly seem to be living up
名不虚传
to that reputation.
一开始什么都不肯说
Wouldn't say a word
直到我威胁告他们妨碍司法
until I accused them of obstruction.
但赞恩在那里租房已经两周了
But Zane has had a suite there for the past two weeks,
他每晚都跟一个女人在一起
and he was with a woman there every night.
好  那女人是谁
Okay, who is this woman?
不知道  她不是登记住客  但是
No idea. She's not a registered guest, but get this.
她不仅是在死亡时间之后回去的
Not only did she arrive after our time-of-death window.
而且尚未离开
She's still there.
开着请勿打扰灯
Privacy light is on.
她肯定还在里面
She must still be here.
纽约警局
NYPD.
请你开下门
Could you open it, please?
-纽约警局  -警察
- NYPD. - Police.
床上有个红发女
There's a ginger in the bed.
母亲
Mother?!
理查德
Richard?
我昨晚
I, um -- I got tired -
等赞恩等累了...
waiting for Zane last night,
于是就  上床睡着了
so I just, uh, crawled into bed.
我完全无法想象他是出了什么事
Never could I imagine what happened to him.
母亲  你为什么
Mother, why are you -- -
你为什么会在赞恩的床上
Why -- Why -- Why were you in Zane's bed?
因为他来上课迟到了
Because he was late for our session.
什么课
What kind of session?
现在都这么叫了吗
Is that what they call it?
-够了  -好吧
- That's enough. - Okay.
母亲  你是说你在跟赞恩·卡侬上床吗
Mother, are you saying you were sleeping with Zane Cannon?
别那么龌龊  理查德
Oh, drop the gavel, Richard!
我是他的演技指导  绝不是他的情妇
I was his acting coach, certainly not his mistress.
那可怜的孩子饰演哈姆雷特完全是自不量力
The poor boy was out of his depth trying to play Hamlet,
所以有人叫他来找我了
so he was referred to me.
赞恩需要我随叫随到
Zane needed me to be on call 24 hours a day.
所以他租下了这间房
So he had this suite
方便我们随时见面
so that we could meet comfortably at any time.
我们将这间屋子变成了莎翁的圣殿
We turned this room into a temple to the Bard.
也成了一种新生的圣殿
It also became a temple to a new life.
什么意思  "新生"
What do you mean, "New life"?
你也知道我是个人生导师
Well, you know I'm a life coach.
我帮赞恩走出了他盛名的迷雾
I helped Zane to just clear out the clutter of stardom
好专注于他的演技
so that he could focus on his craft.
他有提到有什么敌人吗
Did he ever mention having any enemies?
没有  但他有些心魔
No, but he did have some demons, though.
他过去有件什么事
There was something in his past
对他来说是个很大的阻碍
that was a real block for him.
他肯定把那事告诉你了吧
Certainly he told you what the block was.
没有  他对此很保密  甚至害怕
No, he was very secretive about it, frightened, even.
当然  我鼓励他
Oh, of course I encouraged him
去面对心魔了
to engage with those demons, and...
等等  我们上次说话时
Wait a minute. The last time we spoke,
他说做了安排去面对心魔了
he said that he had made arrangements to do just that.
天呐
Oh, dear God.
不会是我怂恿他做了一件
Don't tell me that I might have pushed him into something
害死了他的事吧
that got him killed.
不不  不是那样的
No. No. Nothing like that.
不
No.
-不是吗  -不是  好了
- No? - No, come on.
我送你回家吧  走吧
Let's get you home. Come on.
莱恩  等等
Ryan, wait.
听着
Hey, listen.
该我安排约会之夜了  但我忘了
It's my turn to plan date night, but I forgot,
如果我不能超越他上周的安排
and Castle's gonna lord it over me
卡塞尔肯定要揪着不放了
if I don't outdo what he did last week.
所以  我需要点子
So I need a few ideas.
-等等  盖过塞尔吗  -对
- Wait -- for Castle? - Yeah.
等等
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
他可是
The, uh -- The guy who, uh,
上次万圣节带你
took you on - an urban-spelunking adventure
去城市地铁隧道进行洞穴探险
through the city subway tunnels last Halloween,
还曾雇演员
and then he hired actors
重演电影《C.H.U.D.》的人
to re-enact scenes from the movie "C.H.U.D."
我根本想不出这么好的点子
Yeah, I can't -- I can't come up with stuff like that.
喂
Yo.
赞恩被杀那天早上雇的
I just heard back from that limo driver
豪车司机回我电话了
that Zane hired the morning of his murder.
你不会相信他去了哪的
You'll never believe where he went --
新新监狱
Sing Sing Penitentiary.
他为什么去那儿
Why did he go there?
接一位刚释放的囚犯
To pick up a newly released inmate --
强尼·托罗  他恰好还是
Johnny Toro, who also happens to be
与他疏离的继兄
his estranged older stepbrother.
我们怎么会不知道赞恩有个继兄
How did we not know that Zane had a stepbrother?
异父  异姓
Different dads, different names,
据赞恩的公关表示  他没有声张此事
and according to Zane's publicist, he kept it quiet.
他不想跟此人扯上关系
He didn't want to be associated with this guy.
-那他为什么去监狱  -我不知道
- Then why'd he show up at the prison? - I don't know.
但据豪车司机说
According to the limo driver, though,
场面绝不是幸福的家庭团聚
it was far from a happy family reunion.
虽然车内隔挡竖起来了
The privacy screen was up,
但他听得出托罗在吼赞恩
but he could tell that Toro was yelling at Zane.
他因擅闯蹲了12年
He served 12 years for a B&E.
他在里面慢慢酝酿了对赞恩的恨意
Where he stewed on how much he hated Zane.
看看监狱心理医生的笔记
Check out the prison psychologist's notes.
看来他对赞恩有很多积怨
Apparently, there was a lot of built-up rage against Zane.
根据证据  闯入是两人合伙干的
You know, evidence suggests that this break-in was a two-man job.
警方怀疑过赞恩
Cops suspected Zane
但只有针对托罗的证据
but only had evidence against Toro.
而托罗最终入狱了
And then Toro took the fall.
赞恩搬去了好莱坞  成了大明星
And Zane moves to Hollywood and becomes a movie star.
好吧  叫他进来
All right, get him in here.
我的假释就是这样吗
This what it's gonna be like now I'm on parole?
每天都要受警察的骚扰
Just can't go a day without being harassed by the cops?
你打破了最快再犯罪的纪录就难免了
Not when you set a record for fastest recidivism.
你才出去10小时  就杀了赞恩
You were out all of 10 hours before you murdered Zane.
瞧
See?
我一看到新闻
Soon as I saw the news,
就知道你们会把这事算在我头上
I knew y'all were gonna hang that on me.
是吗  你就这个回应
Really? That's your response?
不是  "哎呦  我继弟死了"
Not -- Not, "Boo-hoo, my stepbrother's dead."
去你的
Screw you.
Z的事我很难过
I'm busted up over what happened to Z.
不  你是气他
No, you're pissed that
那么多年前让你背上罪名
he let you take the rap all those years ago.
我不知道你在说什么  哥们
I don't know what the hell you're talking about, man.
我是哥哥
I was the big brother.
我逼Z不得说出我们去擅闯的事
I made Z keep his mouth shut on that B&E we pulled, man.
叫他去混出个人样来
Told him to make something of himself.
得了  你的监狱心理医生写
Come on, bro. Your prison shrink noted
你对赞恩有强烈的仇怨
that you had a giant hate-on for Zane.
他抛弃了我
He abandoned me.
从不来探视
And not one visit.
不打电话
No calls.
也不给我点钱
Didn't put any money on my books.
什么都没有
Nothing.
跑去做了明星  丢下我自生自灭
Just went off to become a star, and he left me to rot.
豪车司机说他去接你时  你俩吵得很凶
Limo driver said things got pretty heated when he picked you up.
是啊  但豪车司机没听到
Yeah, but what the limo driver didn't hear
我们摒弃前嫌  因为他道歉了
was us squashing our beef, 'cause he apologized,
他说会安排好我的余生
said he would set me up for the rest of my life.
让我等着他先处理好自己的财政问题
Just had to get his financial problems figured out.
什么财政问题
What financial problems?
赞恩银行里有一千万呢
Zane had $10 million in the bank.
他欠国税局1.5千万的退缴税
He owed the IRS 15 mil in back taxes.
他两个月后就要破产了
He was gonna be broke in like two months.
那他为什么没接
Then why'd he walk away
薪酬8百万的电影《安全词》
from an $8 million payday in that "Safe Word" movie
而去拍莎士比亚
to go do Shakespeare?
他说他有捞钱的计划
He said he had a plan to get paid.
是什么大计划
Something big, man.
看来可能是赞恩卷入的挣钱计划
Sounds like whatever money-making scheme Zane was involved in
害死了他
is probably what got him killed.
唯一的问题是
Only question is --
你干什么呢  凯文
What the hell are you doing, Kevin?
嗯  想清楚了
Yeah, figured it out.
-他卷入了什么事吗  -不不
- What he was involved in? - No, no, no, no, no.
萨拉·格蕾丝幼儿园剧目的编舞
The, uh, new choreography for Sarah Grace's preschool play.
好啊  你继续研究
Oh, good. Why don't you keep working on that
我来破案吧
while I solve our homicide?
我要个热狗  什么都不加
Let me get a plain -- plain hot dog.
哈维
Hey, Javi.
嗯
Yeah?
我们被人拍下来了
We are being filmed.
那个被我从犯罪现场赶走的跟踪狂/狗仔
That's that stalker-azzi I chased off the crime scene.
哥们  你叫什么
Hey, buddy, what's your name?
这是公共街道  我有权摄影
This is a public street. I have the right to film here.
没事
Oh, cool, cool, cool.
我们只是想知道你为什么要拍我们
We just want to know why you're filming us.
我跟你们想要的东西一样
Well, I want the same thing you guys do --
赞恩·卡侬的故事的结局
an ending to Zane Cannon's story.
等等
Wait a minute.
你在靠追踪我们追踪调查吗
You've been tracking our investigation by tracking us?
自从赞恩退出了《安全词》
I've been working on an exposé on Zane
来演哈姆雷特  我就一直在对他进行
ever since he dropped out of the movie "Safe Word"
曝光报道
to play Hamlet.
我就知道那个小白脸肯定要砸锅
I knew that pretty boy was a train wreck waiting to happen.
你一直在跟踪赞恩
You've been following Zane?
时不时的  自从他一个月前来到纽约
On and off, ever since he got to New York a month ago.
他被杀当晚你见过他吗
So, did you see him on the night of his murder?
得了
Look, come on.
你想要故事的结局
You want an ending to your story?
告诉我们你都知道什么
Why don't you show us what you got?
或许我们也能帮你
Maybe we can do you a favor.
那个我不稀罕
Yeah, I don't work for favors.
我要采访凶手
I want an interview with the killer.
我还想要有彩虹尾巴的小独角兽呢
Yeah, and I want a baby unicorn with a rainbow tail
给我女儿的
for my daughter.
我们都得失望了  伙计
We're both gonna be disappointed, pal.
行了  把你收集的情报给我们
Come on, man. Show us what you got.
如果情报有用  回头我们逮捕犯人时
If it's any good, when we make an arrest,
让你拍下犯人被抓的样子
we'll let you film the perp walk.
好吗
Deal?
走吧
Let's go for a walk.
我昨天4点左右在剧院拍下了这个
I filmed this yesterday at the theater around 4:00.
那是赞恩被杀害前6小时
That's about six hours before Zane was killed.
-嗯  就在这里  -你拿到我要的东西了
- Oh, yeah, it's right here. - You got what I need?
文身男是谁
Who's the guy with the tats?
不知道
No idea.
让他尽快给我打电话  好吧
Have him give me a call ASAP, all right?
行吗
Cool?
保证不了  伙计  给你
No guarantees, man. Here you go.
-那人是谁  赞恩  -嘿
- Who -- Who's that, Zane? - Yo!
你为何用现金跟他买电话
Why'd you pay him all that cash for the phone?
住手
Come on!
住手  把相机给我
Come on. Give me that camera!
把相机给我  你会把我搞死的
Give me that camera. You're gonna get me killed.
天啊  我还当赞恩是夸大其词呢
Hell, I thought Zane was just being dramatic.
看来我错大发了
I guess I was dead wrong.
我们得让你离开这里了  杰克
Okay, we're gonna need you to leave the room, Jake.
见鬼  也许能采用面部识别
Heck, maybe get that facial recognition.
-打个通缉单  -别动
- We'll print out something. Yeah -- No, no, no.
笔记本放着
Leave the laptop.
不行女士  这是我的财产
No way, lady. This is my property.
杰克  快走
Jake. Now.
老天
Geez.
赞恩到底是跟什么人搅在一起了
What the hell did Zane get himself mixed up with?
只有一个办法能搞清
There's only one way to know.
我们得找出这个神秘人
We got to find this mystery man.
LT  你看见莱恩了吗
Yo, L.T., have you seen Ryan?
他好像在小屋里
I think he's in the box.
艾洛蒂  非常感谢你
éLodie, thank you very much
花时间跟我视频
for taking time to Skype with me.
我就想跟你分享一下
I just -- I wanted to share with you
我对演出的设想
my vision of the play.
你的设想
Your vision?
是的  我认为
Yeah, I see the kids
孩子们在融入生命之圈
as embodying the circle of life.
只是一个花朵舞蹈
It's just a flower dance.
我来跟你演示一下我的意思吧
Let me just show you what I mean.
孩子们叠在一起
Okay, so, the kids -- They're stacked up,
然后绽放花朵  花朵
and then flower, flower.
他们迸发绽放开来
They're -- They're exploding, fanning out.
花朵  花朵  花朵
Flower, flower, flower!
很有趣
Fun!
*花儿朵朵向太阳*
*Flower growing in the sun*
然后他们再围成圈
And then -- then they circle back.
就像巴斯比·柏克萊[好莱坞著名编舞家]那样
Kind of a, you know, Busby Berkeley thing.
凯文
Kevin.
凯文  最大的孩子才五岁
Kevin. The oldest kids are 5.
他们能唱出歌来就很好了
We'll be lucky if they can just sing the song.
我觉得我们要跳出思维定势
I think we need to think outside the box here.
明年再跳吧
Think outside of the box next year,
等我的孩子毕业了的
after my kid has graduated.
艾洛蒂  你要是这样的话
Oh, well, hey, élodie, if you're gonna be like that,
我们说不定得在系统里查查
maybe we need to look into your unpaid parking tickets,
你未付的停车罚单
run them through the system...
凯文
Kevin.
我们还得办案子
We've got that, uh, case that we're working.
好啦  再见
Yeah, okay, bye.
停下
Stop.
离开笔记本
Step away from the laptop.
对  就是赞恩向他购买
Yeah, that's the same guy
一次性手机的那个人
that Zane bought the burner phone off of.
这个录像是四周之前
This footage is dated four weeks ago,
显然赞恩和他的交易一直在进行
so obviously he and Zane had an ongoing arrangement.
等下  我认出这家伙了
Hold up. I-I recognize this guy.
没错  他是亚历桑德罗·古兹曼
Yeah, that's Alejandro Guzman.
他是一个
He's a big shot-caller
末日帮的老大
for a gang called Los Malditos -- The Damned.
他们在西班牙哈莱姆区活动
They operate out of Spanish Harlem.
就是赞恩从小生活的那片地区
That's the same neighborhood that Zane grew up in.
也许他们两个是老相识
Maybe the two of them knew each other back in the day.
在赞恩拍《末日逃亡》系列影片
Before Zane got famous doing all those -
成名前就认识
"Apocalypse Runner" Movies.
我们去西班牙哈莱姆区
We'll go up to Spanish Harlem
看能不能找到这个人
and see if we can track down this guy.
我什么都不知道
I know nothing about nothing.
我们拍到了你和赞恩见面的录像
Well, we got you on video having a meeting with Zane
就在他被杀当天
on the day he was murdered.
你们拍到我杀死他了吗
You got me on video killing him?
我就说嘛  我能走了吗
Yeah, that's what I thought. May I go?
-还不行  -不行
- Not yet. - No.
看看我们做了调查
See, we did our homework.
我们知道你的小兄弟安东尼奥
Yeah, we know that - your little brother Antonio
在州北菲什基尔坐牢
is doing a little stretch upstate at Fishkill.
你妈妈去探视的路途十分遥远
That's a long way for your mother to travel on visiting day,
特别是她膝盖还不好
especially with her bad knees.
你怎么知道我妈的
How do you know about my mama?
我在军队一个老朋友
Oh, I, uh -- I got an old Army buddy
在联邦监狱局工作
who works for the Federal Bureau of Prisons.
他给了我你的档案
He slipped me your file.
哈维  我打赌你的军队朋友
Hey, Javi, I bet your old Army buddy
能把他兄弟转到近一点的监狱
could get his brother transferred closer to the city,
让他妈妈探视起来方便点
make those visits a little easier on mama.
是的  但他必须得愿意开口
Yeah, but he'd have to be willing to talk.
我不跟警察做交易
I don't make deals with police.
那没事
Oh, that's -- that's fine.
我朋友还说了  佐治亚州的联邦监狱
My buddy also tells me that there's a bunch of openings
还有很多空缺
at a federal penitentiary in Georgia.
这估计就得13到14个小时的车程
It would be, like, what, a 13-, 14-hour bus ride?
至少啦
At least.
妈妈好辛苦
Kind of rough on mama.
好吧
All right.
我会说说赞恩  但是我不能说名字
I'll talk about Zane, but I'm not giving you names.
我不能出卖任何一名手下
I'm not ratting anyone out in my crew.
接着说吧
Keep talking.
我很早就认识赞恩
I knew Zane back in the day.
就是街头小混混一个
Just a neighborhood punk.
一个月前  他突然出现了
A month ago, he shows up out of the blue
想要见我的老大
asking to get in touch with my boss.
你老大是谁
Who's your boss?
等等  你是说真正的老大
Hold up, are you talking about...the boss boss?
枭熊吗
El Oso?
我说了不透露姓名
I said no names.
等等  枭熊  贩毒集团的头头
Wait, El Oso? Head of the cartel?
墨西哥政府  缉毒局  联邦调查局
The Mexican government, the D.E.A., the FBI --
都在找这个人
They're all looking for this guy.
他三个月前从墨西哥监狱逃脱
He escaped from prison in Mexico three months ago.
你是说你知道枭熊的藏身之处吗
Are -- Are you saying that you know where El Oso is hiding?
当然不知道
Of course not.
那赞恩为什么要去见你
Then why would Zane come to see you?
因为我手上有消息灵通的人
Because I got a little bird,
我把他们安插到合适的人身边
and I put out my little bird to the right people
直到消息传到那个人
until the message gets to you know who.
很明显你这种消息服务要收费吧
Clearly, you charge - for this little-bird service.
一万美金可以买到一个一次性手机
10 grand gets you a burner.
要是老大想跟你谈  你就能接到一个电话
If the boss wants to talk, you get a phone call.
一个月前  赞恩想跟你的老大谈话
And a month ago, Zane wanted to talk to your boss.
为什么
Why?
某种生意上的提议
Some kind of business proposition.
赞恩甚至让老大跟他面对面地谈事情
Zane even got himself a face-to-face with the boss
因为他确实还是个电影明星
'cause he's a movie star and all.
只是据我所知  事情进展地并不顺利
Only, from what I hear, it didn't go so good.
为什么赞恩被害那天
So why did Zane buy another burner from you
还从你手上买了一次性手机
on the day he was killed?
我不清楚
I don't know.
但要是他再惹老大不高兴
But if he pissed off the boss a second time,
最后死于非命可不能怨我
it's not on me he ended up dead.
豪尔赫 "枭熊" 扎马克纳
Jorge "El Oso" Zamacona.
他既是民族英雄也是魔鬼更是心狠手辣的禽兽
He's part folk hero, part demon, the rest pure monster.
这家伙会杀掉任何与他敌对的人
The man kills anyone who crosses him --
警察  记者还有政客
cops, journalists, politicians.
赞恩肯定是极度缺钱
Zane must have been real desperate for money
才想着要和这种人做交易
to want to do business with this guy.
也许他想充当枭熊在好莱坞新的毒品渠道
Maybe he wanted to be El Oso's new drug pipeline to Hollywood.
也许我们永远都不会知道了
Well, chances are we'll never find out.
我是说如果缉毒局联邦调查局
I mean, if the D.E.A., FBI, and the Mexican government
还有墨西哥政府都找不到他
can't find him,
我们怎么有机会找得到
then what chances do we have?
我会联系我在联邦调查局的熟人
I'll reach out to my Fed contacts.
我们会继续调查枭熊在美国的所有联系
Well, we'll drill down all of El Oso's stateside connections.
好的
Okay.
我想我们的约会之夜要先推迟了
Well, I suppose that puts the brakes on our date night.
是的  抱歉  卡塞尔
Uh, yeah. Sorry, Castle.
没事  我才要道歉
Oh, no, I'm sorry for you.
你都已经把我们的特别之夜安排好了
You're the one who put all the planning into our special evening.
是的  是都安排好了
Yeah, I-I did.
是安排好了
I...Yeah, I did.
我要带我妈妈出去吃饭
You know what? I think I'll take my mother out to dinner,
看能不能让她在经历了这些之后高兴点
maybe cheer her up after all this.
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
你真是个好儿子
You're such a good son.
你就是所有美好的代名词
And you're such a good everything.
哥们
Hey, buddy.
你车停得太近了
Parked a little close.
你看起来...
You look...
好吧  别管我
Okay, don't mind me.
我从副驾驶那边出去就行
I'm just gonna go out the passenger side.
碰到了  我不是故意的
Catch a -- Oh. Didn't mean to --
我不是故意的
Meant to do that.
现在你又动了  谢谢你白痴
Oh, now you move? Thanks, you idiot.
你们是什么人
Who are you guys?
你们要干嘛
What do you want?
我在哪
Where am I?
晚上好
Buenas noches.
你知道我是谁吗
Do you know who I am?
枭熊
El Oso.
听着你给我一条扎马克纳的线索
Listen, you get me a lead on Zamacona,
我们会查下去的
and we will run it.
好的
Yeah.
好  我要挂了  再见
Okay, I got to go. Bye.
你好  亲爱的
Hi, darling.
我知道你很忙  但理查德在这吗
I know you're busy, but is Richard here?
没有  我以为他在跟你吃饭
No. I thought he was at dinner with you.
但他没有来
Yeah, well, he didn't show up,
他的电话直接就是语音信箱
and his cell went right to voicemail.
所以我想他肯定还在专注地查案子
So I figured he must be here immersed in the case.
也有可能他在赏玩他的高级信用卡
Well, he's probably out playing with his fancy new credit card,
我来看下他在哪
but let me check in on him.
阿丽克西斯在我电脑上装了个新的追踪软件
Alexis put new tracking software on my laptop.
我定位一下他的手机
I'll just ping his cell.
可以了
There we go.
找到了  在7号大街与53号街之间
There we go. 7th and 53rd.
这个停车场就在
That's the parking garage across from the restaurant
一个小时前我们约好吃饭的那家餐厅对面
where we were supposed to meet an hour ago.
等我一下
Uh, you know what? Just give me a second.
我是贝克特警监
Hi, uh, this is Captain Beckett.
我想调出53号与7号大街的监控
I need a unit at 53rd and 7th.
我在新闻上看到你了
I saw you on the news.
你跟联邦的人一起
You're working with the Federales
在调查赞恩·卡侬的死
to investigate Zane Cannon's death.
你是说他被谋杀的案子
You mean his murder.
我是说我们知道赞恩
Well, I mean, uh, we know that Zane,
跟你有联系
uh, was in contact with you
在谈一项生意上的提议
about a business proposition
在他英明早逝几个小时前
and that you were in contact with him
你跟他有过联系
just hours before his un-untimely demise.
你以为是我杀了他
You think I killed him.
我们想到了你
You have been associated
毕竟你的过去有着相当多的暴力事件
with a fair amount of violence in your past. -
我想你是想说"史诗般的"
I believe the adjective you're looking for is, uh, "Epic."
史诗般的诸多暴力
An epic amount of violence.
有些人甚至说如《圣经》一般
Some might even say biblical.
所以你也明白为什么你和赞恩打交道
So you can see why your involvement with Zane
会引起警方的注意吧
would have the police curious.
如果我想杀他
If I wanted him dead, I would have cut him open
早在他站在你现在这个位置时我就下手了
when he was standing where you are now.
我也不会用一支笔杀他
I wouldn't kill him with a pen.
那太可爱了
That's cute.
我看起来像是会用可爱的方式杀人吗
Do I look like a man who kills cute?
当然不像
No. No, certainly not.
你看起来也不像是
You also don't look like the sort of man
会用低级的方式吓唬人
who needs to resort to cheap scare tactics.
所以  要不先给我松绑了吧
I mean, why don't you just untie me?
我们坐下来  你告诉我为什么绑我来这
We'll sit down, and you tell me why you brought me here.
谢谢
Thank you.
你们以为赞恩联系我是为了毒品对吗
You think Zane contacted me about drugs, no?
要不然呢
What else is there?
是为了我  枭熊
Yo. Yo mismo. El Oso.
史上最声名狼藉的黑帮老大
The most infamous cartel boss in history.
赞恩想获得你的传记版权
Zane wanted the rights to your life story--
枭熊传记电影
the El Oso biopic.
他觉得饰演我会让他赢得奥斯卡奖
He thought portraying me would win him an Oscar.
-那你怎么回应的呢  -我拒绝了
- So what happened? - I said no.
他可能是很有票房号召力
He may be big box office,
但那家伙根本不会演戏
but the man cannot act.
他成名是因为出演了
He got upstaged by a CGI aardvark
奇幻电影里的一只土豚
in that película De fantasía.
所以我对他提出了一个条件
So I-I made him an ultimatum.
是你让他辞演《安全之词》
You're the one who made him drop "Safe Word"
而去演《哈姆雷特》的
and do "Hamlet."
我得确保他是有实力的
I needed to see that he was serious.
他确实能演戏
That he really could act.
所以我跟他说
So I told him
如果他能在《时代周刊》上获得好评
if he got a good review in the Times,
我就把传记版权给他
my life rights were his.
但他不是在演出首次公映前就联系你了吗
But he had contact with you before the show premiered.
他想再见一次面
He wanted to meet again.
-为什么  -我不知道
- Why? - I don't know.
他说是跟电影有关的事
He said it had to do with the movie,
但我从电话里能听出他很绝望
but I could smell his, uh, desperation through the phone,
特别是在我拒绝他之后
especially when I said no.
那夜晚些时候  他就死了
And later that night, he was dead.
听着  我绑你来这
Pero Mira. I didn't bring you all the way out here
不是为了跟你谈论死者
to talk about Los muertos.
不是吗
You didn't?
不是
No, no, no, no.
当我在电视上看到你时
When I saw you on television,
我就知道命运安排了你进入我的人生
I knew fate had put you in my path,
理查德·卡塞尔
Richard Castle.
我是平民出身
I'm a man of the people.
你是畅销书作家  你为平民写作
You are a popular writer. You write for the people.
所以必须由你来书写我的故事
That's why you must tell my story.
你想要我为你的电影写剧本
You want me to write the script for your movie?
对  会很好玩的
Sí! Sí! It will be fun!
我会把我所有的故事告诉你
I-I will tell you all about myself.
然后你写就是了
And then you will just typey, typey, typey.
大概半年就能完成  可能一年
It should only take six months, maybe a year.
你会跟我一起待在这里
And you will stay here with me!
否则我会把你的尸体寄回家
Or I will mail your body home...
一块一块地
piece by piece.
我们拿到了停车场的监控录像
We got security footage from the garage,
情况不太妙
and it's not good.
天啊
Oh, my...
老天啊
Oh, my God.
那辆车登记在一家空壳公司名下
The Escalade is registered to a shell corp
而且是枭熊的幌子公司
that's a known front for El Oso.
你们能追踪到那辆车对吧
You can track the SUV, can't you?
我们可以  但估计他们现在已经
We can, but they probably swapped cars
不止换过一次车了
at least once by now,
而且现在已经过了两小时
and with a two-hour head start,
搜寻范围已扩至方圆一百公里
we're looking at a 100-mile search radius,
但我们至今为止连目标都没有
and we still have no idea what we're looking for.
你们总能做点什么吧
There must be something that you can do.
理查德命在旦夕呀
This -- This is Richard's life.
YOLO
YOLO.
你太无情了  贝克特
That's cold, Beckett.
不  是卡塞尔的新信用卡
No, uh, Castle's new credit card.
绑架者把他的手机落在车里
The kidnappers left his cellphone by the car,
但他的钱包可能还在身上
but he might still have his wallet with him.
新YOLO卡上
And the new YOLO card
安装了升级版的无线射频识别芯片
has an upgraded RFID chip in it.
所以如果他们经过了收费站或加油站
And if they passed within range of a tollbooth or a gas station...
芯片就会被识别
Then it'll pick up the chip,
我们就能追踪到他了
and we'll be able to track his movement.
好  我去打电话给信用卡公司
All right, I'll call the credit-card company,
看看那张卡有没有在哪被识别到
see if that card's pinged anywhere.
可怜的理查德
Oh, poor Richard.
我都不敢想象他现在正遭受着怎样的折磨
I-I-I can't even imagine how he must be suffering.
你的人生简直就是部莎士比亚戏剧
Your life is, without a doubt, a Shakespearean drama.
我一直都觉得我和麦克白很像
I've always felt - a strong connection to Macbeth.
野心勃勃  但被良心折磨着
Ambitious, but tortured by his conscience.
从你造成的诸多磨难来看
With your relationship to torture,
莎士比亚戏剧中的角色
是一个跛足驼背  面容扭曲  内心邪恶的阴谋家和篡位暴君
我觉得你更像理查三世  你说对吗
I think you're a little more Richard III, am I right?
那个驼子
The hunchback?
我是说更像劳伦斯·奥利弗爵士
I-I was thinking more along the lines of
饰演的那个理查三世
Sir Laurence Olivier.
有我这般成就
A man does not achieve what I have
必然要血染双手
without great personal cost!
豪尔赫  我的意思是
Jorge, I-I only meant you --
你以为我也
Do you think I cannot see
对出现在袖子上的灵魂污点视而不见吗
that the stains on my soul appear upon my sleeve, as well?
你是胆敢对所侍奉的国王冷嘲热讽的
Are you the royal fool who dares believe
那个宫廷小丑吗
he can mock the king he serves?
不  我是那种滑稽的宫廷小丑
No, I'm just the funny kind of court jester.
那你就以死明志吧
Then give me proof of your humility by giving me your life!
理查德
Oh, Ricardo!
真希望你能看到自己现在的表情
I wish you could see your face!
如此独一无二
It's priceless!
你演得太好了
Yes, good one.
理查三世没有幽默感
Richard III had no sense of humor,
但我有幽默感
but I do.
你必须抓住我性格的这些方面
These are the facets of -- of my character that you must capture.
你真应该在电影里演你自己
You know, you should really play yourself in this movie.
要是那样就好了
Oh, if only...
只可惜我是个逃犯
But sadly, I'm a fugitive,
被人迫害  被人误解
persecuted and misunderstood.
直到你向世人展示我的本来面目
Until you tell my story, that is.
现在说一下报酬吧
Now let's talk money, huh?
五百万够吗
Will $5 million be enough?
豪尔赫·扎马克纳  我们是缉毒局
Jorge Zamacona, this is the D.E.A.
你已经被包围了
We have you surrounded.
等一下  别这样
Whoa, whoa, whoa! No, no, no, no!
豪尔赫  等一下
Jorge, wait, wait, wait!
你记得《理查三世》的结局
You remember how "Richard III" ended.
你可以亲手改写自己的结局
You could write your own ending here.
艺术家必须忠于现实生活和自己的内心
An artist must be true to the material and himself.
打开出口
Open the hatch!
在这边
Hey, over there!
他摔倒了  他摔倒了
He's down! He's down!
击倒了三人  卡塞尔在这里
Three down. Castle's here.
卡塞尔先生  你受伤了吗
Are you hurt, Mr. Castle?
没有  我没事  我很好
No, I'm fine. I'm fine. I...
但是可能好不了多久了
But I may not be for long.
那只是本能反应
It was just instinct.
他从我身边跑过去  我就把他绊倒了
He was running by, and I tripped him.
-你做的很好  卡塞尔  -哪里好
- You did good, Castle. - No, not good!
一点都不好
I -- Not good at all!
我绊倒了一个毒枭大佬
I tripped a drug lord.
他是因为我才被抓的
It's my fault he got caught.
缉毒局已经把整栋楼包围了
The D.E.A. had the building surrounded.
就算你没绊倒他  枭熊也跑不掉的
El Oso wasn't getting away, even if you didn't trip him.
可惜  虽然你被绑架的故事很精彩
Sadly, despite your abduction being a fantastic story,
对找到杀害赞恩的凶手还是没什么帮助
we're still no closer to finding out who killed Zane.
我看未必
I wouldn't be so sure about that.
缉毒局从枭熊的仓房里抄出一打一次性手机
The D.E.A. confiscated a dozen burner phones from El Oso's barn.
其中就有他在赞恩被害当天
One of those phones was the one he used to call Zane
给他打电话用的那个
the day he was killed.
所以他们有赞恩的一次性电话号码
So they have Zane's burner phone number,
那我们就可以查出他有没有给其他人打过电话了
which means we could find out if he called anyone else.
是的  他打了
We can, and he did.
打给墨西哥的国际长途
An international line in Mexico,
你们很难相信是打给谁的
and you won't believe who it belongs to --
枭熊的弟弟  海克托·扎马克纳
El Oso's younger brother, Hector Zamacona,
他是个遵纪守法的商人
a legit businessman
只要有机会就会公开谴责枭熊
who publicly condemns El Oso every chance he gets.
他要是在墨西哥  赞恩怎么和他联系
If he's in Mexico, how did Zane connect with him?
赞恩那通电话的两端
Both ends of that call from Zane's phone
都经过了本市的信号塔
pinged off of towers here in the city.
小弟就在市里呢
Baby bro's in town.
-我们知道他现在的位置吗  -还不清楚
- Do we know where he is now? - Not yet.
海克托·扎马克纳可能是
Hector Zamacona might have been
赞恩生前最后一个讲过话的人
the last person to speak to Zane,
所以他可能会知道些什么
which means he may know something.
你老婆怎么来了
Hey, what's your wife doing here?
我不知道  失陪一下
I don't know. Excuse me.
怎么了
So, what's up?
幼儿园的艾洛蒂找我谈了舞台剧的事
éLodie from the preschool called about the play.
有的家长好像有些担心
It seems some of the parents have some...concerns.
他们理解不了我的想法
Ah, yeah. Um, they're, uh, struggling with my vision.
我明天早上给艾洛蒂打电话
I'll -- I'll call éLodie in the morning.
带她过一遍
I'll walk her through it.
其实  他们已经决定改变思路了
Actually, they have decided to go a different direction.
等等  他们是把我炒了吗
Wait, they're firing me?
明天就要演出了
The play's tomorrow.
这是艾洛蒂的主意  对吧
It's that éLodie, isn't it?
那个魔鬼妈妈管家教协会的事还不够  非要
PTA's not enough for that mom-ster. She has to --
凯文  这是所有家长的意思
Kevin, it's all the parents.
大家都喜欢你的热情
Everybody loves your enthusiasm.
只是  孩子们还在上幼儿园
It's just, they're preschoolers.
他们不是百老汇明星
They're not Broadway stars.
所以不穿软底鞋了
So no soft-shoe?
不穿软底鞋了
No. No soft-shoe.
-好吧  -过来
- Okay. - Come here.
-这种事情时有发生  -是啊
- It happens. - Yeah.
这么说  除了惹毛了一个爱杀人的毒枭大佬之外
So, other than pissing off a homicidal drug lord,
你觉得我们的惊喜约会夜怎么样
how did you enjoy our surprise date night?
你是说让一个
Are you saying you planned
在逃的毒枭绑架我是你安排的
my abduction by a fugitive cartel leader?
是的  还有我们英勇解救你这一切都是
Yeah, complete with the daring rescue and everything.
很有意思  对吧
It was fun, huh?
我觉得和瓜达拉哈拉来的屠夫
I don't think date night counts
共进烛光晚宴不算约会之夜吧
when it's a candlelit dinner with the butcher of Guadalajara.
我还准备了别的
Well, I'll -- I'll plan something else.
别的
Something else?
你根本没准备
You didn't have a plan!
你发现我们这样压力多大吗
Do you realize how pressure-filled this is,
总想打败对方
always trying to top each other?
这是我们乐趣源泉的一半
That's half the fun of it.
我们的竞争燃起热情之火
Our rivalry is what fuels the passionate fire...
-竞争  -你说什么
- Rivalry. - What?
竞争
Rivalry.
兄弟之间的竞争
Between two brothers.
什么  什么竞争
What? What rivalry?
豪尔赫·扎马克纳也就是枭熊
The one between Jorge "El Oso" Zamacona
和他弟弟海克托之间的竞争
and his brother, Hector.
竞争关系可以解释
A rivalry would explain
为什么赞恩会同时和兄弟俩合作
why Zane was working with both brothers,
但是我们怎么证明呢
but how -- how do we prove it?
我只要找到一个证据
I just need to find one piece of evidence
证明我的思路正确
to see that I'm on the right track.
这就行了
And that could be it.
我的西班牙语有点生疏了
All right, my Spanish is a little rusty,
但我的翻译软件显示
but my handy translator says...
海克托·扎马克纳一直和他兄弟的老婆睡觉
Hector Zamacona's been sleeping with his brother's wife.
自从枭熊逃亡开始
They have been shacking up
他们就一直在鬼混
ever since El Oso went on the run.
所以赞恩可能夹在
So Zane might have been caught
两兄弟的竞争之间
in a rivalry between the brothers,
因此导致了他的被杀
and that's what got him killed.
海克托想要的不仅是枭熊的老婆
Hector wants more than just El Oso's wife.
根据缉毒局的说法
According to the D.E.A.,
他所有的  呃  合法生意
all of his, uh, "Legitimate" Businesses --
都被怀疑是为了掩盖洗钱
They're suspected fronts for money laundering.
所以  既然大哥在逃亡
So with big brother on the run,
豪尔赫·扎马克纳
枭熊
海克托可以争取由自己来管理家族
Hector can make a play to rule the family in his place.
但是海克托无法真正得到实权
But Hector can never truly own the throne
除非他的哥哥死了
until his brother is dead.
一个有权势的家族  一个贩毒帝国
A powerful family, a cartel for a kingdom,
两兄弟困在一场控制权的争斗中
two brothers locked in a battle for control.
伙计们  这就像这出戏一样
Guys, this is just like the play.
哈姆雷特的父亲被他兄弟所杀
Hamlet's father is killed by his brother,
而他兄弟夺取了王位
who then takes the throne
娶了他亡兄的妻子
and marries the dead brother's wife.
有人说莎士比亚是永恒的经典是有原因的
There's a reason - they say Shakespeare endures.
这就是一处现实版的哈姆雷特
This is a real-life "Hamlet."
好  除去主题的相似性不说
Okay, so, thematic similarities aside,
为什么海克托需要赞恩来除掉枭熊
why would Hector need Zane to take down El Oso?
因为海克托不知道去哪找他的哥哥
Because Hector didn't know where to find his brother.
而电影明星赞恩面对面见过枭熊
And movie star Zane had a face-to-face with El Oso.
这让赞恩成为了完美的特洛伊木马
Making Zane the perfect Trojan Horse
来引导海克托找到他哥哥
to lead Hector to his brother.
为什么赞恩会同意做这件事
Why would Zane agree to do that?
他想要出演枭熊的电影
He wanted to star in the El Oso movie.
钱
Money.
海克托值几亿美元
Hector's worth hundreds of millions.
赞恩现在就需要钱  不能等到三年后
Zane needed the money now, not in three years,
电影可以挣钱的时候
when the movie could get off the ground.
所以海克托提出来以解决赞恩钱的问题
So Hector offers to solve Zane's money problems
来交换赞恩带他找到枭熊
in exchange for Zane leading him to El Oso.
但枭熊拒绝与赞恩见面
But El Oso refuses to meet with Zane.
然后  与其等着看赞恩出演哈姆雷特的影评
Then, rather than wait to see if Zane's "Hamlet" Reviews
是否好到可以与枭熊见面
are good enough to meet with El Oso,
海克托决定掩盖踪迹
Hector decides to cut his losses.
在这个家族里  这就意味着杀人
Which, in this family, translates to murder.
我哥哥沾血的手给我们的家族带来了耻辱
My brother's bloody hand has brought shame on our family.
我们更愿意把他关起来
We're better off with him back in a cage.
是啊  我的意思是  你肯定更愿意这样
Well, yeah, I mean, - you're definitely better off.
你甚至都不用来偿还赞恩·卡侬的税债
You didn't even have to pay for Zane Cannon's tax debts.
我为什么要替一个电影明星交税
Why would I pay a movie star's taxes?
来让他带你找到你哥哥
To get him to lead you to your brother.
这样你就能杀了枭熊
That way you could kill El Oso
接管家族生意了
and take over the family business,
就像你接管了那你哥哥的老婆一样
much in the same way you took over the family bed.
而当赞恩不能再一次与枭熊见面后
And when Zane couldn't get a second meeting with El Oso,
他成了你的后患  所以你杀了他
he was a loose end, so you killed him.
我没有杀赞恩
I did not kill Zane.
我们知道赞恩用一个一次性手机给你打了电话
We know that Zane called you from a burner phone
就在他被杀几小时前
hours before he was killed.
我们也知道你把1500万美元
We also know that you put $15 million
放进了一个企业财产账户
into a holding account.
跟他税务账单的数额相同
The exact amount of his tax bill.
假设我确实跟他有协议
Let's say I did have a deal with him.
我为什么要在哈姆雷特试映一周前杀他呢
Why would I kill him a week before "Hamlet" Previews?
按你所说  好的影评可以让他
According to you, good reviews would have gotten him
跟我哥哥再次见面
another meeting with my brother.
但那就会让赞恩难以得到
But that would have put Zane out in the cold
那个可能让他赢得奥斯卡的角色
for his Oscar-winning role.
所以即使有一大笔报酬
And even with a big payoff, it would have been tough
让他放弃那个角色仍然可能很困难
to get him to walk away from that role.
除非你承诺他无论如何他都可以保留那个角色
Unless you promised him he could keep it anyway.
当你哥哥死了
With your brother dead,
他的生命权就会转交给你
the life rights would revert to you.
我一点都不在乎枭熊的传记片
I could care less about the El Oso biopic.
我告诉他  他就算当导演我也不在乎
I told him he could direct it for all I cared.
等等  你告诉赞恩
Wait, you -- you told Zane
他能自导自演他的梦想中的项目
he could star in and direct his dream project?
只是我猜赞恩已经把这个工作
Only I guess Zane had already promised the job
承诺给了其他人
to someone else --
一个不是很愿意失去它的人
someone who would not be happy to lose it.
它们令我痛心
O, woe is me.
与我现在所见到的
T'have seen what I have seen --
不  你必须更投入
No. Y-You've got to feel it more.
这不是随便一个和你在社交软件上分手的人
This isn't just some guy who broke up with you on Snapchat.
哈姆雷特背叛了你
Hamlet betrayed you.
他从来没有爱过你
He -- He never loved you.
你去进尼姑庵罢  对吗
"Get thee to a nunnery," Right?
哈姆雷特夺走了你的一切
Hamlet took everything from you.
你肯定对这一幕感同身受
That's certainly a scene you can relate to,
不是吗  切尔洛夫女士
isn't it, Ms. Cherloff?
这是非公开彩排
Uh, this is a private rehearsal.
我们20分钟后会休息  你能让我们先完成吗
We have a break in 20. Can you let us finish?
我觉得你可能已经完事了
I think maybe you are finished.
虽然我们很尊敬莎翁
All due respect to the Bard,
不过我们带来了一个我们自己的故事
we're here with a tale of our own --
一个带有背叛和嫉妒  经典的悲剧
one with betrayal and jealousy, though sadly classic.
一个真正有天赋的导演看着
A truly gifted director watches
她以前的同学成为好莱坞升起的新星
as her former classmate's star rises in Hollywood,
而她还在为每个机会拼命争取
while she fought like hell for every opportunity.
我热爱我的工作
I love what I do.
所以如果赞恩选择了健身馆而不是演艺学校
So what if Zane made millions
而挣了几百万美元又怎么样呢
because he chose the gym over acting school?
我创造了艺术
I make art.
但当赞恩向你要求选他来演哈姆雷特
But when Zane asked you to cast him as Hamlet,
你拒绝了他  不是吗
you told him no, didn't you?
是的  直到他让我相信他适合这个角色
Yes, until he convinced me he was right for the part.
用让你导演枭熊传记片这个千载难逢的机会吗
By offering you your big break directing the El Oso biopic?
但那只是个空头支票
But it was a Hollywood promise.
一文不值
Not worth a damn.
告诉我  他是向你坦白
Tell me, did he confess to you
他会亲自执导
that he would be directing the picture on his own,
还是只是告诉你你丢掉了这份工作
or did he just tell you you lost the job?
都不是
Neither.
因为这些都没有发生过
Because it didn't happen.
我根本不知道什么枭熊项目
I-I don't know anything about an El Oso project.
那么你如何解释你笔记本电脑上的搜索历史
Then how do you explain the browser history on your laptop?
还有你壁橱里沾着赞恩的血的鞋子
Or the shoes in your closet with Zane's blood on them?
你们根本不知道让赞恩出演这剧
You have no idea what a risk it was
风险有多高
putting Zane in this play.
唯一值得的回报就是
A-And the only thing that made it worthwhile
导演那部电影
was directing that movie.
结果他告诉我  他要执导
A-And then he tells me that -- that he's gonna do it
而我可能只是创造了
a-and I'm left with maybe the worst production
史上最差劲《哈姆雷特》
of "Hamlet" in history.
我的职业生涯基本断送了
I mean, my career is as good as over.
你们知道作为一个女人进军导演界
Do you have any idea how difficult it is as a woman
有多么艰难吗
to break into directing film?
而他就这么轻描淡写地夺走了我的机会
A-And he took away my shot like it was nothing.
那晚我听着他的声音
I heard him that night
毁掉舞台剧上
torturing maybe the most beautiful words
最美丽的台词  我发狂了
ever written for the stage, and I just snapped.
这边走  切尔洛夫女士
This way, Ms. Cherloff.
这是在说彩排结束了吗
Is that a wrap on rehearsal?
你还在因为被赶出莎拉·格雷斯的
You still mad about being fired
学前表演生气吗
off Sarah Grace's preschool play?
只是在生自己的气  我发过誓不做那种爸爸的
Ah, only at myself. I swore I'd never be that dad.
什么  那种傻乎乎地
What, the kind - that makes an ass of himself
为了自己女儿跳得像一朵花的吗
by dancing around like a flower for his daughter?
不  那种
No, the kind...
那种只想着自己想要什么
the kind who gets caught up in what he wants,
而不是他的孩子想要什么
not what his kid does.
好了  我们走
Yeah, okay, let's go.
爹地
Daddy!
瞧瞧我的小向日葵
Look at my little sunflower!
你好  哈维叔叔
Hey! Uncle Javi!
亲爱的
Ohh! Hey, baby.
我刚准备出发
Hey. I was just leaving.
你们不是应该已经到那里了吗
Aren't you guys - already supposed to be there?
她不想去
Uh, she didn't want to go.
不肯说为什么  她只是想见你
Wouldn't say why. She just wants you.
宝贝
Uh...hey, sweetie.
听着  如果你不想唱就不用唱
Look, y-you don't have to sing if you don't want to.
这是原则
That's the law.
但是如果我不唱你会不开心
But you'll be sad if I don't.
什么  不会
What? No.
我想更可能的是她忘记台词了
I think it's more she forgot the words.
你想让我帮你回忆台词吗
Oh, do -- do you want me to help you remember the words?
我会和你一起唱  准备好了吗
Okay, I'll do it with you. Ready?
把手准备好
Okay. Get your hands ready.
*花儿  花儿  花儿笑*
*Flower, flower, Flower fun*
*花儿长在阳光照*
*Flower growing in the sun*
*雨滴落下云儿高*
*Raindrops fall from clouds up high*
我们来转个圈
We spin around!
*蜜蜂整日嗡嗡叫*
*And all day long, the bees buzz by*
真不错
Nice!
我觉得你准备好了小家伙
I think you're ready, S.G. All right?
那么我们去表演吧
So we'll go to the play?
-好  -她准备好了
- Yeah. - She's ready.
这次我想
This time I want to...
这个约会之夜和我想要的一模一样
This date night is everything I dreamed it would be.
介于最近的各种刺激
Well, given all the recent excitement,
我觉得一个安静的夜晚会是个不错的转变
I thought that a quiet night in would be nice for a change.
你还是做了点计划的  是什么
You did plan something. What is it?
快闪族  寻宝  码头骗子
Flash mob, treasure hunt, land shark?
不不  我发誓  我完全不知道谁在敲门
No, no, I swear. I don't know who's at the door.
谢谢
Oh. Thank you.
不  卡塞尔  那是另一张信用卡吗
Oh, no. Castle, is that another credit card?
我已经受够YOLO了
Because I am YOLO'd out.
不是信用卡
Not a credit card.
剧本笔记  传记材料
Script notes, biographical materials.
是枭熊寄来的
It's from El Oso.
贝克特  你知道这意味着什么吗
Beckett, you know what this means?
他还是想让你写他的剧本
He still wants you to write his script.
而且他不想杀我
And he doesn't want me dead.
直到他看到第一版草稿
Until he reads the first draft.
那倒是
Well, there's that.
"这些资料只涵盖了
"These materials only cover
我们的前两部电影
the first two acts of our movie.
第三幕即将发生
The third act is yet to come,
而且会有个爆炸性的开场
and it starts with a bang."
埃斯波
Hey, Espo.
真的吗
Seriously?
枭熊刚从联邦拘留逃脱
El Oso just escaped federal detention.
什么
What?!
他们应该叫这个人胡迪尼[逃脱魔术大师]
They should call this guy El Houdini.
等等  卡塞尔  你要去哪儿
Hey, wait, Castle, where are you going?
-约会之夜还没有结束  -对我来说已经结束了
- Date night's not over yet. - It is for me.
我要去开始写这个剧本
I got to start writing this script.
码字  码字  码字
Typey, typey, typey!